<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kubernesto</title><link>https://kubernesto.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Kubernesto</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kubernesto.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Productivity Story - Part 3</title><link>https://kubernesto.github.io/posts/productivity-story-part-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubernesto.github.io/posts/productivity-story-part-3/</guid><description>Welcome to part 3 of the My Productivity Story series. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read parts 1 and 2, you should go and do it! But I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk only the about tools I have used on this one. So I don&amp;rsquo;t think is going to be needed.
To Do tools Apple Reminders I already mentioned in part 1 of this series that my first tool was the Reminders app on my iPhone.</description></item><item><title>My Productivity Story - Part 2</title><link>https://kubernesto.github.io/posts/productivity-story-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubernesto.github.io/posts/productivity-story-part-2/</guid><description>Last week, I published a post about my productivity story and some of the methodologies I used in University and the first years of my career. I finished the blog with the mix of GTD and MIT (Most Important Task) method setup that I had for a while. It was a bit painful to update the three most important tasks for each context each time I completed a task. So, I decided to stop doing it.</description></item><item><title>My Productivity Story - Part 1</title><link>https://kubernesto.github.io/posts/productivity-story-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubernesto.github.io/posts/productivity-story-part-1/</guid><description>So I decided that I want to share my entire productivity system here in my blog. But my system is a mix of a lot of stuff I have learned since I was in the university. So I will try to tell that story from the start and all the things I have found since then.
Everything started one afternoon when I had a lot of things to do for the university, and had no idea where to start.</description></item><item><title>New schedule for blog posts</title><link>https://kubernesto.github.io/posts/new-schedule/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubernesto.github.io/posts/new-schedule/</guid><description>Hi, dear readers! I don&amp;rsquo;t have any analytics tool in this blog, so you could be two or two hundred (I&amp;rsquo;m leaning towards the first one, but why not dream with the latter?). Starting today I have decided to post a new blog every two weeks (so every other Friday). Why? Because if I don&amp;rsquo;t try to build a habit around this, I will just procrastinate a lot about it. That means there will be posts with fewer words and less preparation, but also, I think I will get better with practice.</description></item><item><title>My way of doing pomodoros</title><link>https://kubernesto.github.io/posts/pomodoros/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubernesto.github.io/posts/pomodoros/</guid><description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard about The Pomodoro Technique and know some Italian. In that case, you may wonder: &amp;ldquo;Is this a cooking blog?&amp;rdquo;. But no, I will not talk about the tasty tomatoes (Pomodoro in Italian) today. I will speak of a time management method created by Francesco Cirillo that consists of having deep focus sessions of approximately 25 minutes and a break of 5 minutes. Also, every 4 sessions, a more extended break of 15 minutes.</description></item><item><title>How to set up a Free Todoist account with GTD</title><link>https://kubernesto.github.io/posts/gtd-todoist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubernesto.github.io/posts/gtd-todoist/</guid><description>Introduction First of all, I want to be clear that this is not a paid post about Todoist or David Allen Company. I decided to write this post because I&amp;rsquo;m a GTD (Getting Things Done) aficionado, and I happen to use Todoist as the tool for my GTD system.
The idea of this post is to explain how to do an initial set-up for GTD in a Todoist free account.</description></item><item><title>Using Sealed Secrets to encrypt secrets in a Helm Chart values file</title><link>https://kubernesto.github.io/posts/secrets-charts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubernesto.github.io/posts/secrets-charts/</guid><description>Reading the title of this post you may ask yourself: &amp;ldquo;Why would I want to encrypt a secret and put it on a values file?&amp;rdquo;. And to that, I would respond: &amp;ldquo;Well, to push it to GitHub (or any equivalent), of course&amp;rdquo;. And you would ask me again: &amp;ldquo;But why would I want to push a secret to a public (or private, even) repository?&amp;rdquo;, and I will answer: &amp;ldquo;Well! Because GitOps!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kubernesto.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubernesto.github.io/about/</guid><description>Welcome Hi all! And welcome to my blog. My name is Ernesto González and I am an AppDev Consultant for Red Hat, where my jobs is to help customers deploy their applications on top of OpenShift. I also enjoy developing video games and had worked in Pod Escape, a video game deployed on top of OpenShift for the Red Hat Summit of 2020. You can find it here: https://arcade.redhat.com.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://kubernesto.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubernesto.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Connect with me on LinkedIn or send me an email at ernesto.gonzalez33@icloud.com.</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://kubernesto.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kubernesto.github.io/projects/</guid><description>Here are some of the projects I have worked on:
Pod Escape: Endless Runner Game developed using Godot in which you are a Kubernetes pod trying to escape from the deletion of the namespace you were deployed. Co-designer and Co-developer. Playable here. Marinera: A subset of the FIWARE platform with CI/CD tooling to make it easier to deploy on top of OpenShift. Contributor. Bookinfo Operator: A Kubernetes Operator capable of deploying the Bookinfo application.</description></item></channel></rss>